Petr Sulilo

Senior Software Engineer | Team Leader | 10+ years of experience | Android, Java, Kotlin

+1 (310) 569-9464



in linkedin.com/in/peter-sulilo



Sacramento, CA, USA

Fully authorized to work in the USA without visa sponsorship

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Self-employed | 2022 - Present | Sacramento, CA, USA

- Collaborated with a team to develop client-side Android applications for the telecommunications industry.
- Designed and implemented features, ensuring high performance and user experience across various devices.
- Successfully completed projects on time, contributing to increased client satisfaction and repeat business.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MegaFon | Full-time | Sep 2021 - Oct 2022 · 1 yr 1 mo | Moscow, Russia

- Led team of 7 engineers that achieved a 20% reduction in time-to-market.
- The app has been downloaded over 10 million times and has received over 525,000 reviews on Google Play.
- · Responsible for setting team goals, consulting leadership, and implementing multi-module architecture.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Finbridge | Full-time | May 2019 - Jul 2021 · 2 yrs 3 mos | Rostov-on-Don, Russia

- Mentored and assisted 8 team members, fostering a productive environment and driving high-quality software delivery within an Agile framework.
- Led a comprehensive refactoring of a key project, updating over 90% of the codebase, resulting in a modern, highly responsive user interface and significantly improved user experience.
- Implemented a robust error monitoring system, increasing the crash-free rate from 82.3% to 99.98%, and reduced the time for the testing department to identify and document issues by 300%.
- Built and maintained a high-performing engineering team, utilizing technologies such as Java, Kotlin, MVVM, MVP, Google Architecture Components, Moxy, Dagger 2, Koin, RxJava, Coroutines, Room, Retrofit, Sentry, AppMetrica, Firebase Crashlytics, and Firebase App Distribution.

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer with a heavy focus on mobile. I have over 10 years of experience, and a lot of it is in fintech and telecom, so I know that area pretty well. In the past several years, I've extensively worked with easily extensible, scalable, testable, multi-module Android applications.

In my recent teams, I have non-technical responsibilities as well, including coaching, mentoring, and interviewing engineers. I have helped 5 engineers get promoted in the last 3 years.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

Don State Technical University Sep 2008 - May 2011

Bachelor of Science in Computer Software Engineering

Rostov State Economic University (RINH) Sep 2004 - May 2008

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mentalstack | Full-time | Aug 2018 - May 2019 · 10 mos | Taganrog, Russia

- Developed a Video/Audio converter for Android OS.
- Integrated and optimized Ffmpeg and MediaCodec, expanding functionality to include an audio converter.
- Increased supported audio formats from 2 to 7 and video formats from 3 to 7, resulting in a 30% increase in user base.
- Worked with Android NDK, C/C++, Android SDK, Kotlin, Java, delivering a robust and versatile media conversion tool.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Wi-Fi k9 | Full-time | Jun 2016 - Oct 2017 · 1 yr 5 mos | United States (Remote)

- Developed OpenVPN for Android OS.
- Redesigned the user interface, improving the user experience and increasing the app's average rating from 3.2 to 4.2 stars.
- Worked with Android NDK | C/C++ | Java, Git, JSON, REST API, Firebase Crashlytics, Google AdMob.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Progressive technologies | Full-time | 2015 - 2016 · 1 vr 1 mo | Rostov-on-Don, Russia

- Developed and supported mobile apps for iOS and Android.
- Programmed in Java (Android SDK) and Objective-C (iOS SDK).
- Set up system authorization using the Captiva portal on Mikrotik routers.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Svyazgazavtomatika LLC | Full-time | 2013 - 2015 · 2 yrs 2mos | Rostov-on-Don, Russia

- Designed, maintained, and developed reports (classes, functional modules, and groups) using ALV Grid Control.
- Developed custom search tools (Search Help's), PDF forms, an extension of standard SAP R/3 functionality.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SUPPORT ENGINEER

DSL LLC | Jan 2009 - Apr 2011 · 2 yrs 4 mos | Rostov-on-Don, Russia | Part-time

• Diagnosed hardware and software, repaired modules, restored software to normal operation, designed LANs, and configured network routers.

COMPUTER LAB ASSISTANT

RSEU "RINH" | Jan 2007 - Nov 2007 - 11 mos | Rostov-on-Don, Russia | Part-time

- Development of a software tool for the preparation of financial statements
- LAN design